Inventory of the Thomas H. (Thomas Hawkins) Johnson Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Thomas H. (Thomas Hawkins) Johnson Papers
1963-1990
92047
Hoover Institution Archives
52 manuscript boxes, 1 motion picture film reel (21.0 linear feet)
Writings, correspondence, notes, memoranda, studies, technical reports, journal articles, and other printed matter, relating to physics, nuclear and other energy sources, nuclear weapons, laser technology, the Strategic Defense Initiative, arms control, and scientific policy in the United States during the presidential administration of Ronald Reagan. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Johnson, Thomas H. (Thomas Hawkins), 1943-1990.
Access
Collection is open for research. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1992.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1943 November 11 Born, Massachusetts
1965 Graduated from U.S. Military Academy, West Point, and commissioned as a second lieutenant
1968 MS in Physics, University of California, Davis
1974 PhD in Applied Physics, University of California, Davis
1974-1976 Chief, physics section, Weapons Laboratory, Kirtland Air Force Base, New Mexico
1975 Permanent professor, U.S. Military Academy, West Point, New York
1977-1980 Returned to U.S. Military Academy, West Point, New York, and taught in Department of English
1980 Director, Science Research Laboratory, U.S. Military Academy, West Point, New York
1981-1982 Deputy to the president's science advisor and deputy director, White House Office of Science and Technology Policy
1981-1983 Executive director, White House Science Council
1982 Associate Dean, academic research, U.S. Military Academy, West Point, New York
1990 Awarded Legion of Merit, Member, International Board of Editors, Science and Global Security
1990 June 26 Died, Washington, D.C.
1990 Fall Poems, Sewanee Review. Posthumously published and dedicated to his memory
Scope and Content of Collection
Acquired in 1992, the Thomas Hawkins Johnson papers consist of correspondence, journal articles, memoranda, notes, studies, technical reports, writings and other printed matter, relating to physics, nuclear and other energy sources, nuclear weapons, laser technology, the Strategic Defense Initiative, arms control, and scientific policy in the United States during the presidential administration of Ronald Reagan.
Alternate Forms Available
Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
United States Military Academy. Science Research Laboratory.; United States. Army--Officers.; White House Science Council.; Arms control.; Lasers--Military applications.; Moving-pictures.; Nuclear energy.; Nuclear weapons.; Physics.; Power resources.; Science--United States.; Strategic Defense Initiative.; United States--Defenses.; United States--Military policy.
- "The MAC Method, 1966." Report, Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory, New Mexico. (Box-folder 1: 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes related articles, 1965-1971
- "Calculation of Toroidal Magnetic Field Configurations," University of California, Livermore, 1967 (Folder 1: 2)
  Report
- "Computational Problems in Magnetohydrodynamics (MHD)," John Killeen, 1972 (Folder 1: 3)
  Article
- "Numerical Simulation of Plasmas with Periodic Smoothing in Phase Space," J. Denavit, 1971 (Folder 1: 4)
- "Relativistic Plasma Simulation-Optimization of a Hybrid Code," J. P. Boris, undated (Folder 1: 5)
- Reports of Energy Research Advisory Board (ERAB) magnetic fusion panel, 1978-1983 (Folder 1: 6)
  Includes information bulletins
- Articles, notes, recommendations, reports, and statement relating to work of magnetic fusion panel, 1983-1992
- Naval Research Laboratory (NRL), Washington, D.C., undated, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  Articles and reports relating to striation work
- R. W. Klib, 1975-1977 (Folder 2: 2)
  Articles, outlines, and report relating to late-time propagation and striation spectra, plasma instabilities and striations, striation diffusive decay, striation growth and decay, and effect of low-B plasmas
- "Linear and Nonlinear Theory of Ionospheric Irregularities," Pradeep Kumar Chaturbedi, 1976 (Folder 2: 3)
  Dissertation
- Hane transport coefficients, 1975 (Folder 2: 4)
  Report. Also includes a report on collisional momentum and energy transfer rates
- Naval Research Laboratory (NRL) ionosphere papers, undated (Folder 2: 5)
- "Two-Dimensional Lagrangian Hydrodynamic Difference Equations," William D. Schulz, undated (Folder 2: 6)
- "Numerical Simulation of the Earth's Atmosphere," Cecil E. Leith, undated (Folder 2: 7)
- "Numerical Study of Two Fluid Rayleigh-Taylor Instability," Bart J. Daly, 1967 (Folder 2: 8)
- W. P. Crowley, 1967-1969 (Folder 2: 9)
  Articles
- "Slip Instability," Anthony A. Amsden and Francis H. Harlow, 1964 (Folder 2: 10)
- "Numerical Study of Large-Amplitude Free-Surface Motions," Francis H. Harlow and J. Eddie Welch, 1966 (Folder 2: 11)
- "Particle-in-Cell Computing Method for Fluid Dynamics," Francis H. Harlow, undated (Folder 2: 12)
- CMHD approach to high-altitude blast waves, 1974 (Folder 2: 13)
- Hull, undated (Folder 2: 14)
  Graphs and notes
- "Air Force Weapons Laboratory (AFWL) Multiburst Model," Daniel A. Matuska, Michael M. Tower, and Charles E. Needham, circa 1975 (Folder 2: 15)
  Articles and notes
- "Magnetohydrodynamic Equilibria in Sharply Curved Axisymmetric Devices," J. D. Calleen and R. A. Dory, 1972 (Folder 2: 16)
- "Computation of Hydromagnetic Equilibria with Finite Pressure in Minimum-B Systems," John Killeen and Kenneth J. Whiteman, 1966 (Folder 2: 17)
- "Finite Beta Equilibria in Axially Symmetric Toroidal Plasma Containment Devices," S. Fisher and J. Killeen, 1971 (Folder 2: 18)
- "A Bifurcation Problem in E-Layer Equilibria," B. Marder and H. Weitzner, 1970 (Folder 2: 19)
- "Computer Simulation of Plasma Confinement in an Atellarator," C. G. Smith and A. S. Bishop, undated (Folder 2: 20)
- "Mixed Eulerian-Langrangian Method," R. M. Frank and R. B. Lazarus, undated (Box-folder 3: 1)
- "Numerical Simulation of the Weibel I in One and Two Dimensions," R. L. Morse and C. W. Nielson, 1971 (Folder 3: 2)
- Two-stream instability calculations, 1969-1971 (Folder 3: 3)
- "The Numerical Solution of Radial Transport Equations for Toroidal Plasmas," John Killeen, 1971 (Folder 3: 4)
  Article. Includes a related article about plasma transport, 1972
- "Numerical Simulation of Relativistic Electrons Confined in an Axisymmetric Mirror Field," M. Brettschneider, J. Killeen, and A. A. Mirin, 1972 (Folder 3: 5)
- "Computation of E-Layers and Plasma Equilibria in Astron," David V. Anderson, John Killeen, and Marvin E. Rensink, 1971-1972 (Folder 3: 6)
- "Hybrid Simulations of Quasineutral Phenomena in Magnetized Plasma," J. A. Byers, B. L. Cohen, W. C. Condit, and J. D. Hanson, 1977 (Folder 3: 7)
- Articles about Fokker-Planck equation and mirror confined plasma, 1957-1970 (Folder 3: 8)
- Symposium on atmospheric effects sponsored by Defense Nuclear Agency (DNA), San Diego, California, 1973 April 9-13 (Folder 3: 9)
  Memorandum and program
- "A Numerical Fluid Dynamics Calculation Method for All Flow Speeds," Francis H. Harlow and Anthony A. Amsden, 1971 (Folder 3: 10)
  Article and report
- "Satellite Communications in a Scintillated Environment,", 1976 (Folder 3: 11)
  Report and related article
- Barium clouds, 1974-1976 (Folder 3: 12)
  Articles and reports
- "Implication of Pseudo-Classical Diffusion for Toroidal Confinement Devices," S. Yoshikawa and N. C. Christofilos, undated, 1970 (Folder 3: 13)
  Article and related materials
- EXB instability, 1963-1974 (Folder 3: 14)
- "A Possible Mechanism for Energy Losses in a Tokamak Device," O. P. Pogutse, 1971 (Folder 3: 15)
  Article. Includes review of a related article
- "The Electromagnetic Interchange Mode in a Partly-Ionized Collisional Plasma," Mary K. Hudson and Charles F. Kennel, 1975 (Folder 3: 16)
- "Numerical Modeling of the Drift and Deformation of Ionospheric Plasma Clouds and Their Interaction with Other Layers of the Ionosphere," K. H. Lloyd and G. Haerendel, 1973 (Folder 3: 17)
- CTR diffusion data, undated, 1967 (Folder 3: 18)
  Articles Miscellany, 1966-1976. Articles and bibliography relating to ionospheric irregularities, plasma in the magnetosphere, and plasma computer simulation
- S. R. Goldman, undated and 1976-1978 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  Papers, proposal, and reports
- H. Okuda et al., 1976-1977 (Folder 4: 2)
  Articles and papers
- Diffusion, 1975-1976 (Folder 4: 3)
  Working notes
- Strips, undated (Folder 4: 4)
  Article and notes
- Background plasma physics – draft waves, 1963-1978 (Folder 4: 5)
  Papers and reviews
- Writings by Thomas Johnson
  - "The Role of Anomalous Transport Mechanisms in Striation Decay,", 1975 (Folder 4: 6)
  - "Drift Waves, the Universal Instability and Anomalous Diffusion in Ionospheric Striations,", 1977
- Physical Dynamics, Inc. (PDI), 1975-1978, undated (Folder 4: 7)
  Graph, letter, outline, report, and related materials
- F. W. Perkins, 1975-1976 (Folder 4: 8)
  Articles (co-authored with others)
- LMSC ionosphere background, 1975-1976 (Folder 4: 9)
  Reports
- Ionosphere/Magnosphere, 1980 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  Technical report
- "The Prospects for ICF Power," John S. Foster, Jr., American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS) symposium, San Francisco, 1980 (Folder 5: 2)
- "Economic Potential of Inertial Fusion," John H. Nuckolls, 1985 (Folder 5: 3)
- "Inertial Confinement Fusion (ICF): Feasibility and Utility for Power Production," remarks by John Nuckolls, 1979-1981 (Folder 5: 4)
  Includes article, memorandum, and review of an article
- Greg Canavan, 1979 (Folder 5: 5)
  Memoranda and remarks
- Inertial Confinement Fusion (ICF) program, Department of Energy (DOE)
  - Articles, letter, notes, and program recommendations, 1979-1980, undated (Folder 5: 6)
  - Politics, 1979-1980 (Folder 5: 7)
    Articles, letter, memoranda, notes, report, review committee report, 1986
  - William Happer, Jr., review committee report, 1986 (Folder 5: 8)
  - Alexander Glass, 1979, 1985-1987 (Folder 5: 9)
    Articles, remarks, report, and statement
- Miscellany, 1973-1986
  Articles, brochure, graph, clipping, journal, memoranda, notes, paper, remarks, and report relating to fusion studies
- Report of the ad hoc experts review group--Recommendations on the NOVA program, undated (Box-folder 6: 1)
- William Happer, Jr., review committee report, 1985-1986 (Folder 6: 2)
  Includes related materials
- Jaws correspondence and background, 1979 (Folder 6: 3)
  Letter and list of Energy Systems Acquisition Advisory Board (ESAA) members
- Inertial Confinement Fusion (ICF) program, 1975-1985
  Articles, clippings, conference papers, letters, memoranda, notes, outline, reviews, and statistical data relating to research, strategies, and politics of this program at various institutions and government agencies, such as Argonne National Laboratory, Department of Energy, Lawrence Berkeley Laboratory, Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory, SRI International, Naval Research Laboratory, and Universities of Rochester and Wisconsin
- List of Energy Research Advisory Board (ERAB) Inertial Confinement Fusion (ICF) panelists, technical consultants and others, undated (Box-folder 7: 1)
  Agenda, message, notes, and related materials
- Plasma papers, 1975-1983 (Folder 7: 2)
- Naval Research Laboratory papers, 1975-1984 (Folder 7: 3)
- Inertial Confinement Fusion (ICF) program review, 1982 January (Folder 7: 4)
  Letter, note, and related materials
- Ion fusion accelerator research, plasma and laser systems research, ion beam propagation and focusing, and overview of ICF program, 1975-1984
  Articles, graph, journals, memoranda, notes, program, and reports
- Advanced Isotope Separation (AIS) Program (Box 8)
  - Background materials, 1979-1982 (Folder 8: 1)
  - Paperwork, 1980 (Folder 8: 2-3)
    Graph, letter, and related materials. Includes 1 photographic print depicting unidentified individuals, undated
- W. J. Schafer Associates, Inc., circa 1979 (Folder 8: 4)
  Report on assessment of pulsed compressed KrF lasers
- Inertial Confinement Fusion (ICF) background papers and administrative files, 1971-1985
  Articles, notes, paper, and report
- Articles, journals, papers, and reports relating to laser fusion, report of Advanced Isotope Separation (AIS) program, laser and plasma research, Energy Research Advisory Board (ERAB) report, 1975-1986
- Heavy Ion Fusion (HIF) and Particle Beam Fusion Program (PBFA), 1978-1980 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  Articles, letter, papers, program, and report
- University of Rochester, 1977-1985 (Folder 9: 2)
  Articles, graph, letter, memoranda, and program
- Advanced Isotope Separation (AIS) draft materials, 1981-1983 (Folder 9: 3)
  Articles, graphs, report, and schedule
- Lawrence Livermore Laboratory--Nova project, 1977-1986 (Folder 9: 4)
  Articles, brochure, fact sheet, financial records, letter, memoranda, and report
- Articles, letter, and reports relating to Inertial Fusion Program and laser plasma coupling, 1983-1985
- Fusion hybrid reactors project, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 10: 1)
  Article, letters, list of members of committee on fusion hybrid reactors, memoranda, and report
- Report on the fusion-fission hybrid reactor, 1986
- Energy Research Advisory Board (ERAB) fusion panel and magnetic fusion energy research, 1984-1987
  Articles, graphs, reports, and other materials
- National Academy of Sciences, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 11: 1)
  Agenda, list of members of committee on fusion hybrid reactors, memoranda, minutes of meetings, outline, papers, reports, schedule, and summary of significant studies
- Thomas H. Johnson, 1986
  Magnetic fusion panel report
- Budget, 1983-1984
- Miscellany, 1977-1986
  Articles, brochure, journal, letter, memoranda, notes, proposal, remarks, and report relating to magnetic and plasma fusion program
- Thomas H. Johnson--Magnetic fusion panel (Box 12)
  - Agenda, article, letter, list of technical panel members, memoranda, note, outline, report, and statement, 1986
  - Correspondence, 1983
- Magnetic Fusion Advisory Committee report, 1983
- Committee on fusion hybrid reactors, 1985
  Agenda of meeting, articles, list of names and addresses of committee members, memoranda, remarks, and statement of work
- Fusion program, plasma physics, and other related matters, 1984-1986
  Data, graph, memoranda, newsletter, paper, report, and statement
- Fusion hybrid and tritium breeding fusion reactors, magnetic fusion, hybrid blanket concept, fission tokamak hybrid, and development of fusion energy, 1980-1987 (Box 13)
  Article, budget, graphs, letter, memoranda, notes, printed matter, report, testimony, and other materials
- Comprehensive kinetic model of the electron-beam-excited Xenon chloride laser, plasma physics, magnetic fusion, and MFE program strategy, 1981-1989 (Box 14)
  Articles, data sheets, graphs, journal, letters, memoranda, notes, remarks, and reports
- "A Comprehensive Kinetic Model of the Electron-Beam-Excited Xenon Chloride Laser," Thomas Johnson, Harry E. Cartland, and Thomas C. Genoni, undated (Box-folder 15: 1)
- Energy Research Advisory Board (ERAB) fusion panel, 1986 (Folder 15: 2)
  Letter, list, memoranda, and report
- Miscellaneous materials relating to thermonuclear research, fusion program, and energy issues, 1973-1987
- Laser systems, plasma, and Inertial Confinement Fusion (ICF) (Box 16)
  - Conference proceedings, laser digest, reports, and related materials, 1975-1979
  - Conference proceedings, laser digest, paper, report, and summary of facilities construction schedules, 1975-1986 (Box 17)
  - Laser digest, letter, paper, report, and technical proposal, 1974-1980 (Box 18)
- Nuclear debate and laser program, 1978-1986 (Box 19)
  Conference proceedings, military cost handbook, outline, paper, report, technical proposal for laser design study, and miscellany
- Soviet Military Power, 1981-1988 (Box 20)
- Report on laser research, 1978
- Whence the Threat to Peace, 1987
- "Strategic Stability under the Conditions of Radical Nuclear Arms Reductions,", 1987
- "New Electronic Transition Laser Systems," 1978, and "High Resolution Imaging and ASAT,", 1982
- PH 385 B laser physics, 1978 (Box-folder 21: 1)
- DASA reaction rate handbook, 1948 (Folder 21: 2)
- Report on electronic transition laser system, 1978
- Writings by Thomas Johnson
  - Technical Trends and Strategic Policy, with Sidney Drell, 1988
  - "Inertial Confinement Fusion: Review and Perspective,", 1984
  - "XeC1 Laser Modeling," with Thomas Genoni, 1984
  - "The Natural History of the Space Shuttle,", 1988
  - "Scaling of KrF for Inertial Confinement Fusion," with Allen Hunter II and Robert Hunter, Jr., 1986
  - "A Comprehensive Kinetic Model of the Electron-Beam-Excited Xenon Chloride Laser," with Harry Cartland, Thomas Genoni, and Allen Hunter, 1989
- Note, 1992
- "Time-Reversible Difference Procedures," O. Buneman, 1967 (Box-folder 22: 1)
- "Particle-Code Models in the Nonradiative Limit," Clair W. Nielson and H. Ralph Lewis, undated (Folder 22: 2)
- "Collective Transport in Plasmas," John M. Dawson, Hideo Okuda, and Bernard Rosen, undated (Folder 22: 3)
- Bruce Langdon, 1972-1979 (Folder 22: 4)
  Paper and related materials
- "Recent Developments in the Computational Aspects of MHD Stability," R. Grimm, remarks, Second European Conference on Computational Physics, Garching, near Munich, Germany, 1976 April 27-30 (Folder 22: 5)
- "A Continuously Rezonable Fluid Solver in Moving Orthogonal Coordinates with Time Dependent Metric," D. V. Anderson, 1974, and "Solutions of Transient Problems in Free Surface Hydrodynamics," M. J. Fritts and J. P. Boris, 1977 (Folder 22: 6)
- Flux-Corrected Transport (FCT), 1971-1978 (Folder 22: 7)
  Papers
- Strategic defense initiative and space systems, 1983-1989
  Clippings and photocopies of articles, letter, and news bulletins
- History of defense strategy (Box 23)
  - Early history of nuclear arms race, 1953, 1975, undated (Folder 23: 1)
  - "Evolution of the U.S. Military Space Program, 1945-1960," B. W. Augenstein, 1982 (Folder 23: 2)
  - "The Delicate Balance of Terror," Albert Wohlstetter, circa 1959 (Folder 23: 3)
  - "Discriminate Deterrence," report of the Commission on Integrated Long-Term Strategy, 1988 (Folder 23: 4)
  - "The Development of Nuclear Strategy," Bernard Brodie, 1959 (Folder 23: 5)
  - "Springtime of the Nuclear Debate," William L. Borden, undated (Folder 23: 6)
  - "Bernard Brodie: America's Prophetic Strategic Thinker," William P. Snyder and John A. MacIntyre, Jr., 1981, and "The Necessity of Knowledge," M. Mitchell Waldrop, 1984 (Folder 23: 7)
  - "The Los Alamos Primer,", undated (Folder 23: 8)
    Notes
  - "The Gaither Committee and the Policy Process," Morton H. Halperin, 1961 (Folder 23: 9)
  - Hans Bethe, 1959-1983 (Folder 23: 10)
    Articles by Hans Bethe and others in his honor
  - "Choosing a Strategy for World War III," Thomas Powers, 1982 (Folder 23: 11)
  - The nuclear barons, undated (Folder 23: 12)
    Collection of articles
  - "The Russian Revolution--Fifty Years After: Origins of the Cold War," Arthur Schlesinger, Jr., undated (Folder 23: 13)
  - Laser program, nuclear weapons, space weapons system, and strategic defense, 1975-1992
    Articles, course and lecture outline, journals, letter, memorandum, notes, press release, and reports
- Force, structure, strategy, deterrence--Europe, 1950, 1982-1987, undated (Box-folder 24: 1)
- Security and arms control issues, missile system, nuclear defense policy, and strength of Soviet defense system, 1972-1988, undated
  Announcement by the president on strategic weapons systems, article, clipping, journals, letters, notes, outline, press release, reports, and testimony
- Proliferation, 1978-1986 (Box-folder 25: 1)
- Test ban, 1982-1988 (Folder 25: 2)
- Verification, 1985-1988 (Folder 25: 3)
- Civil defense, 1982 (Folder 25: 4)
  Articles and newsletter
- Article, book reviews, comments on strategic defense, journal, letter, memoranda, press release, and report, 1979-1988
- Arms control
  - Treaty compliance, 1985 (Folder 25: 5)
    Article and clipping
  - "Strategic Arms Reductions," Michael M. May and George F. Bing, 1987 (Folder 25: 6)
  - "Arms Control, Compliance, and the Law," George Bunn and Wolfgang K. H. Panofsky, 1988 (Folder 25: 7)
  - "The Grand Negotiation,", undated (Folder 25: 8)
  - INF treaty between President Ronald Reagan and Mikhail Gorbachev, Washington, D.C., 1987 December 7-10 (Folder 25: 9)
- Address, articles by Hans Bethe, Sidney Drell and others; clipping; speech; report; and testimony relating to nuclear arms control and preservation of peace, negotiations for the Strategic Arms Limitations Treaty (SALT), and future of U.S.-Soviet relations, 1978-1985
- Writings by Thomas Johnson (Box 26)
  - "A Comprehensive Kinetic Model of the Electron-Beam-Excited Xenon Chloride Laser," with others, 1989
  - "Inertial Confinement Fusion: Review and Perspective,", 1984
  - "Kinetics Simulation of High-Power Gas Lasers," with others, 1979
  - "The Natural History of the Space Shuttle,", 1988
  - "Scaling of KrF Lasers for Inertial Confinement Fusion," with others, 1986
  - "Technical Trends and Strategic Policy," with Sidney Drell, 1988
- Articles and reports relating to energy plan and least-cost energy strategy, 1979-1989
- Richard Garwin, 1958-1981
  Agenda, article, commencement address, comments, correspondence with Thomas Johnson, draft papers, letters, list of papers and testimony, memoranda, report, and speech relating to arms race, strategic options, and the issue of defense. Includes letter to President Jimmy Carter
- Fusion, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 27: 1)
  Article, graphs, letters, memoranda, notes, papers, press release, report, and speech
- Fusion briefing, magnetic fusion, and nuclear weapons, 1988-1989
  Articles, graph, letters, memoranda, notes, and reports
- Research and Development funding, 1988 (Box-folder 28: 1)
- Arms race, laser and fusion research, science and fusion energy policy, role of science and technology in American life, European security, and high power radio frequency research, 1981-1998
  Articles, bulletin, clippings, course outline, journal, letters, lists, memoranda, newsletters, notes, reports, and miscellany
- Carbon dioxide, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 29: 1)
  Articles, clipping, list of participants in green house effect meeting, and notes
- Special Isotope Separation (SIS) Project, 1989 (Folder 29: 2)
  Articles, chart, clipping, graphs, letter, notes, outline, statement, and testimony
- Artificial intelligence, computational physics, energy research and possible sources of power, international security and arms control, and laser technology, 1973-1989
  Articles, journals, letters, memoranda, press release, and report. Includes colored photocopies of a building and the interior of a scientific research laboratory
- White House Science Council (WHSC) (Box 30)